(Wooden swords clacking)
Yah! Left high. left low.
(Swords clanging. men shouting)
Right low. lunge right.
You break anything.
the septa will have my head.
- What is...
- (Screaming)
Your sister knew perfectly well
we were to leave today.
- How she could forget...
- She didn't forget.
She's with her dancing master.
She's with him every morning.
She always comes back with scrapes
and bruises. She's so clumsy.
- Hush!
- (Swords clanging. men yelling)
Go back to your room.
Bar the doors and do not open them
for anyone you do not know.
- What is it? What's happening?
- Do as I told you.
Run!
- (Man) This way!
- (Door banging)
(Screaming)
Left. right. Rah!
- Now you are dead.
- You said right.
but you went left.
- And now you are a dead girl.
- Only 'cause you lied.
My tongue lied.
My eyes shouted the truth.
- You were not seeing.
- I was so. I watched. but you...
Watching is not seeing. dead girl.
The seeing. the true seeing.
that is the heart of swordplay.
(Door opens)
Arya Stark. come with us.
Your father wants to see you.
And why is it that Lord Eddard
is sending Lannister men
in place of his own?
- I am wondering.
- Mind your place. dancing master.
- This is no concern of yours.
- My father wouldn't send you.
And I don't have to go
with you if I don't want.
(Laughs) Take her.
Are you men or snakes.
that you would threaten a child?
Get out of my way. little man.
I am Syrio Forel...
Foreign bastard.
...and you will be speaking to me
with more respect.
Kill the Braavosi. Bring the girl.
Arya child. we are done
with dancing for the day.
Run to your father.
Bloody oafs.
- Begone now. Arya.
- Come with me. Run.
The first sword of Braavos does not run.
- (Wood clatters)
- What do we say
to the god of death?
Not today.
Go.
(Men moaning)
(Swords ringing)
(Men screaming)
Not today. Not today.
(Gasps)
Stay away from me.
I'll tell my father.
I'll... I'll tell the queen.
(Chuckles) Who do you think sent me?
(Horses neighing)
Needle.
There she is.
- What do you want?
- I want you. wolf girl.
- Come here.
- Leave me be.
- My father's a lord. He'll reward you.
- She'll reward me - the queen!
- Stay away!
- (Gasps)
(Door clanging. creaking)
Lord Stark. you must be thirsty.
Varys.
I promise you it isn't poisoned.
Why is it no one ever trusts the eunuch?
Not so much. my lord.
I would save the rest. if I were you.
Hide it. Men have been known
to die of thirst in these cells.
What about my daughters?
The younger one seems
to have escaped the castle.
Even my little birds cannot find her.
- And Sansa?
- Still engaged to Joffrey.
Cersei will keep her close.
The rest of your household though...
all dead. it grieves me to say.
I do so hate the sight of blood.
You watched my men
being slaughtered and did nothing.
And would again. my lord.
I was unarmed. unarmored
and surrounded by Lannister swords.
When you look at me
do you see a hero?
What madness led you to tell the queen
you had learned the truth
about Joffrey's birth?
The madness of mercy.
- That she might save her children.
- Ah. the children.
It's always
the innocents who suffer.
It wasn't the wine
that killed Robert. nor the boar.
The wine slowed him down
and the boar ripped him open.
but it was your mercy
that killed the king.
I trust you know you're
a dead man. Lord Eddard?
The queen can't kill me.
Cat holds her brother.
The wrong brother. sadly.
And lost to her.
Your wife has let the Imp
slip through her fingers.
If that's true.
then slit my throat
and be done with it.
Not today. my lord.
Tell me something. Varys.
Who do you truly serve?
The realm. my lord.
Someone must.
(Door creaks. clangs)
It's Othor. without a doubt.
The other one is Jafer Flowers. my lord.
less the hand the wolf tore off.
Any sign of Benjen
or the rest of his party?
Just these two. my lord.
Been dead awhile. I'd say.
- Mmm.
- The smell.
(Sniffs) What smell?
There is none.
If they'd been dead for a long time.
wouldn't there be rot?
- We should burn them.
- Snow's not wrong. my lord.
Fire will do for them.
The wildling way.
I want Maester Aemon
to examine them first.
You may be a coward. Tarly.
but you're not stupid.
- Get them inside.
- You heard him.
Lord Commander.
Maester Aemon
awaits you in his chambers...
A raven from King's Landing.
Come on. move 'em out.
Bring me a horn of ale. Snow.
and pour one for yourself.
The king is dead.
Is there any word of my father?
Sit.
Lord Stark has been
charged with treason.
They say he conspired
with Robert's brothers
to deny the throne to Prince Joffrey.
I hope you're not thinking
of doing anything stupid.
Your duty lies here now.
My sisters were in King's Landing too.
I'm sure they'll be
treated gently.
(Varys) Your father has proved to be
an awful traitor. dear.
King Robert's body was still warm
when Lord Eddard began plotting
to steal Joffrey's rightful throne.
He wouldn't do that.
He knows how much
I love Joffrey. He wouldn't.
Please. Your Grace.
there's been a mistake.
Send for my father. He'll tell you -
the king was his friend.
Sansa sweetling. you are innocent
of any wrong. We know that.
Yet you are the daughter of a traitor.
How can I allow you to marry my son?
(Pycelle) A child born of a traitor's seed
is no fit consort for our king.
She is a sweet thing now. Your Grace.
but in 10 years who knows
what treasons she may hatch?
No. I'm not. I'll be
a good wife to him. you'll see.
I'll be a queen just like you. I promise.
I won't hatch anything.
The girl is innocent. Your Grace.
She should be given a chance
to prove her loyalty.
(Sighs)
Little dove. you must write to Lady Catelyn
and your brother. the eldest.
- what's his name?
- Robb.
Word of your father's arrest
will reach him soon. no doubt.
Best it comes from you.
If you would help your father.
urge your brother
to keep the king's peace.
Tell him to come to King's Landing
and swear his fealty to Joffrey.
If... If I could see my father.
talk to him about...
You disappoint me. child.
We have told you
of your father's treason.
Why would you want
to speak to a traitor?
I only meant that...
What will happen to him?
- That depends.
- On...
- On what?
- On your brother.
And on you.
Treason?
Sansa wrote this?
It is your sister's hand.
but the queen's words.
You are summoned to King's Landing
to swear fealty to the new king.
Joffrey puts my father in chains.
now he wants his arse kissed?
This is a royal command. my lord.
- If you should refuse to obey...
- I won't refuse.
His Grace summons me to King's Landing.
I'll go to King's Landing.
But not alone.
Call the banners.
All of them. my lord?
They've all sworn to defend my father.
have they not?
They have.
Now we see
what their words are worth.
Yes.
Are you afraid?
I must be.
Good.
- Why is that good?
- It means you're not stupid.
(Cawing)
You've had this since dawn?
He sent it to me. not you.
- I've only shown it to you as a courtesy.
- A courtesy?!
My husband has been taken prisoner.
- My son intends to declare war.
- A war?
Your son against the Lannisters?
You should go to him.
Teach him patience.
Ned rots in a dungeon
and you speak of patience?
He is your brother by law!
Does family mean nothing to you?
Family means everything to me.
And I will not risk Robin's life
to get caught up in another
of your husband's wars.
- I'm hungry.
- Hush now. darling.
You just ate.
You will not support us. then?
Do I understand you correctly?
- But I'm hungry!
- Soon. love. soon.
You're always welcome here. sister.
But if you're asking me
to send men from the Vale to fight...
That is what I ask.
Go on. sweet.
Time for your bath.
I'll feed you after.
If you fear for the safety of your son...
Of course I fear
for the safety of my son!
Are you an idiot?
They killed my husband.
You say they shoved
your boy from a window.
- These people will do anything.
- And that is why we have to stop them.
The knights of the Vale
will stay in the Vale
where they belong.
to protect their lord.
(Tyrion whistling a tune)
Will you shut up?
There's hill tribes all around here.
If I'm going to die. it may as well be
with a song in my heart.
I should just take your food
and leave you here.
Eh?
- What would you do then?
- Starve. most likely.
You don't think I'd do it. do you?
What do you want. Bronn?
Gold? Women?
Golden women?
Stick with me and you'll have them all.
for as long as I'm around
and not a moment longer.
But you knew that.
That is why you so valiantly
took up arms to defend my honor.
Fair enough.
But don't go looking
for me to bend the knee
and "my lord" you
every time you take a shit.
I'm not your toady
and I'm not your friend.
Though I would treasure
your friendship.
I'm mainly interested
in your facility with murder.
And if the day ever comes
when you're tempted to sell me out.
remember this -
whatever their price.
I'll beat it.
I like living.
(Whistles)
- (Rustling)
- (Bronn whispers) Tyrion.
Tyrion.
(Birds chirp. flutter)
Come. share our fire.
Help yourselves to our goat.
When you meet your gods.
you tell them
Shagga. son of Dolf.
of the Stone Crows sent you.
I am Tyrion. son of Tywin
of Clan Lannister.
How would you like to die.
Tyrion. son of Tywin?
In my own bed.
at the age of 80
with a belly full of wine
and a girl's mouth around my cock.
(Laughing)
(All laughing)
Take the halfman.
He can dance for the children.
Kill the other one.
No. no. no. no. no!
My... My house is rich and powerful.
If you see us through these mountains.
my father will shower you with gold.
We have no use
for a halfman's promises.
Halfman maybe. but at least I have
the courage to face my enemies.
What do the Stone Crows do?
Hide behind rocks and shiver
when the knights
of the Vale ride by?
Are those the best weapons
you could steal?
Good enough for killing sheep.
if the sheep don't fight back.
Lannister smiths shit better steel.
You think you can win us over
with your trinkets?
That trinket is worth more
than everything your tribe owns.
But if you help us.
Shagga. son of Dolf.
I will not give you trinkets.
I will give you this.
What is "this"?
The Vale of Arryn.
The lords of the Vale
have always spat upon the hill tribes.
The lords of the Vale want me dead.
I believe it is time
for new lords of the Vale.
(Crow cawing)
(Ser Alliser) Now there's a rare sight...
Not only a bastard.
but a traitor's bastard.
- Jon. no!
- Jon. stop. put it down!
Blood will always tell.
You'll hang for this. bastard.
I told you not to do anything stupid.
You're confined to quarters. Go.
(Barking. whining)
Ghost. what's wrong?
Is someone out there?
(Whining and growling)
(Snarling)
(Growling)
Commander?
(Barks. whines)
Stay.
Hello?
- Who's there?
- (Whines)
- Lord Commander?
- (Door slams)
(Barking)
(Growling)
(Mormont) Snow?
Commander!
(Yelps)
(Screaming)
Move!
(Men yelling. women screaming)
(Grunts)
(Screaming and yelling continue)
What did they do?
Lamb men make good slaves.
Khal Drogo will make a gift
of them to the slavers.
and the slavers will give us gold...
...and silk. and steel.
(Daenerys) I thought the Dothraki
didn't believe in money.
Gold to hire ships. Princess.
ships to sail to Westeros.
(Women screaming)
Jorah. make them stop.
- Khaleesi?
- You heard me.
These men have shed blood for their khal.
Now they claim their rewards.
She is a lamb girl. Khaleesi.
The riders do her honor.
If her wailing offends the Khaleesi.
I will bring you her tongue.
Princess. you have a gentle heart.
but this is how it's always been.
I do not have a gentle heart. ser.
Do as I command
or Khal Drogo will know the reason why.
(Rakharo speaks Dothraki)
- Come.
- (Man speaks Dothraki)
- What do you want done with them?
- Bring her to me.
And those women there.
You cannot claim them all. Princess.
I can.
and I will.
(Man speaks Dothraki)
(Dothraki continues)
(Drogo speaks Dothraki)
Moon of my life.
Mago says you haven taken his spoils.
a daughter of a lamb man
who was his to mount.
Tell me the truth of this.
Mago speaks the truth.
my sun and stars.
I have claimed many daughters this day...
...so they cannot be mounted.
This is the way of war.
These women are slaves now...
...to do with as we please.
It pleases me to keep them safe.
If your riders would mount them.
let them take them for wives.
Does the horse mate with the lamb?
The dragon feeds on horse and lamb alike.
You are a foreigner.
You do not command me.
I am Khaleesi. I do command you.
(Drogo snickers)
See how fierce she grows?
That is my son inside her.
the stallion that will mount the world.
filling her with his fire.
I will hear no more.
Mago. find somewhere else
to stick your cock.
A Khal who takes orders
from a foreign whore is no Khal.
(Speaks Dothraki)
I will not have your body burned.
I will not give you that honor.
The beetles will feed on your eyes.
The worms will crawl through your lungs.
The rain will fall on your rotting skin...
...until nothing is left of you but bones.
First you have to kill me.
I already have.
My sun and stars is wounded.
A scratch...
...moon of my life.
Where are the healers?
This is the bite of a fly.
I can help the great rider with his cut.
The Khal needs no help
from slaves who lie with sheep.
She is mine. Let her speak.
(Speaks English) Thank you. silver lady.
(Speaks English) Who are you?
I am named Mirri Maz Duur.
I was the godswife of this temple.
Witch.
My mother was
godswife here before me.
She taught me how
to make healing smokes and ointments.
All men are of one flock.
so my people believe.
The great shepherd sent me
to earth to heal his...
Too many words.
A witch's words poison the ears.
Lamb or lion.
his wound must be washed
and sewn or it will fester.
Let her clean your wound.
my sun and stars...
...it makes me hurt to see you bleed.
(Men chatting)
For 30 years I've been making
corpses out of men. boy.
I'm the man you want
leading the vanguard.
Galbart Glover will lead the van.
The bloody wall will melt
before an Umber
marches behind a Glover.
I will lead the van
or I will take my men
and march them home.
You are welcome
to do so. Lord Umber.
And when I am done
with the Lannisters.
I will march back north.
root you out of your keep
and hang you for an oathbreaker.
Oathbreaker. is it?!
I'll not sit here and swallow insults
from a boy so green he pisses grass.
(Snarls)
(Screaming)
(Snap)
(Screams)
My lord father taught me
it was death to bare steel
against your liege lord.
But doubtless the Greatjon
only meant to cut my meat for me.
Your meat...
is bloody tough.
(Jon Umber chortles)
(All laughing)
- What is it? What's happened?
- Shh. it's all right.
- Where are you going?
- South. For Father.
- But it's the middle of the night.
- The Lannisters have spies everywhere.
I don't want them to know
we're coming.
- They have more men than we do.
- Aye. they do.
Can't I come with you?
I can ride now.
You've seen me riding.
And I won't get in the way. I...
There must always be
a Stark at Winterfell.
Until I return that will be you.
You are not to leave the castle walls
while we are gone. Do you understand?
Listen to Maester Luwin.
Look after your little brother.
- I will.
- I'll send letters whenever I can.
but if you don't hear from me.
don't be scared.
Until I return.
How long have you been
hiding out there?
Robb will be looking for you
to say goodbye.
- They've all gone away.
- They'll be back soon.
Robb will free Father
and they'll come back with Mother.
No. they won't.
(Bran) Please watch over Robb.
And watch over
all the other men from Winterfell.
And Theon too. I suppose.
You hear them. boy?
The old gods are answering you.
- What are you doing here?
- They're my gods too.
Beyond the Wall.
they're the only gods.
- Even slaves are allowed to pray.
- You're not a slave.
Well. your friend
did put a knife to my throat.
I'm not complaining. little lord.
just telling truths.
What did you mean
about hearing the gods?
You asked them.
they're answering you.
Shh.
- Open your ears.
- (Leaves rustling)
It's only the wind.
Who do you think
sends the wind if not the gods?
They see you. boy.
They hear you. (Sighs)
Your brother will get
no help from them where he's going.
The old gods have
no power in the South.
The weirwoods there were all
cut down a long time ago.
How can they watch
when they have no eyes?
(Running footsteps)
(Osha giggles)
Well. there's a big man.
He has giants' blood
in him or I'm the queen.
- Go back and find your clothes. Hodor.
- (Laughs)
- Go dress.
- Hodor.
Are there really giants beyond the wall?
Giants and worse than giants.
I tried telling your brother.
he's marching the wrong way.
All these swords.
they should be going north. boy.
North. not south!
- The cold winds are rising.
- (Leaves rustling)
They were touched by white walkers.
That's why they came back.
That's why their eyes turned blue.
Only fire will stop them.
- How do you know that?
- I read about it in a book...
a very old book
in Maester Aemon's library.
- What else did the book say?
- The white walkers
sleep beneath the ice
for thousands of years.
And when they wake up...
And when they wake up. what?
I hope the Wall's high enough.
(Men chattering in camp)
Summer snows. my lady.
Robb's brought the North with him.
The river lords are falling back
with Jaime Lannister at their heels.
And Lord Tywin is bringing around
a second Lannister army from the South.
Our scouts confirm
it's even larger than the Kingslayer's.
One army or two.
the kings in the North
threw back hosts 10 times as large.
Mother!
You look well.
Lady Catelyn. you're a welcome sight
in these troubled times.
We had thought not
to meet you here. my lady.
I had not thought to be here.
I would speak with my son alone.
I know you will forgive me. my lords.
You heard her!
Move your arses!
Come on. out.
You too. Greyjoy.
Are you bloody deaf?
Have no fear. my lady.
We'll shove our swords
up Tywin Lannister's bunghole
and then it's on
to the Red Keep to free Ned.
- You old devil. Rodrik.
- Jon.
You're not wasting away. are you?
I remember the day
you came into this world.
red-faced and squalling.
And now I find you leading a host to war.
- There was no one else.
- No one?
Who were those men I saw here?
- None of them are Starks.
- All of them are seasoned in battle.
If you think you can
send me back to Winterfell...
Oh. would that I could.
There was...
a letter.
From Sansa.
From the queen. you mean.
- There's no mention of Arya.
- No.
How many men do you have?
18.000.
If I go to King's Landing
and bend my knee to Joffrey...
You would never
be allowed to leave. No.
Our best hope.
our only hope.
- is that you can defeat them in the field.
- And if I lose?
Do you know what happened
to the Targaryen children
- when the Mad King fell?
- They were butchered in their sleep.
On the orders of Tywin Lannister.
And the years have not made him kinder.
If you lose.
your father dies. your sisters die.
we die.
Well. that makes it simple. then.
I suppose it does.
From here it might be best
if Bronn and I continue alone.
Best for Tyrion. son of Tywin.
Not best for me.
If the halfman betrays us.
Shagga. son of Dolf.
will cut off his manhood...
And feed it to the goats. yes.
All right. then.
Time to meet my father.
- Tyrion.
- Uncle.
Father.
The rumors of your demise
were unfounded.
Sorry to disappoint you.
And who are these...
companions of yours?
This is Shagga. son of Dolf.
chieftain of the Stone Crows.
Timett. son of Timett.
ruler of the Burned Men.
This fair maid is Chella.
daughter of Cheyk.
leader of the Black Ears.
And here we have Bronn. son of...
You wouldn't know him.
May I present my lord father.
Tywin. son of Tytos of House Lannister.
Lord of Casterly Rock
and Warden of the West?
Kind of you to go to war for me.
You left us no choice.
The honor of the house was at stake.
Your brother would never have
submitted to capture so meekly.
We have our differences. Jaime and I.
He's braver. I'm better-looking.
He's been covering himself in glory.
Jaime smashed the river lords
at the Golden Tooth.
and now lays siege to Riverrun.
Catelyn Stark's homeland.
- And the Starks? Lord Eddard?
- Is our hostage.
He will lead no armies
from his dungeon cell.
How did my sweet sister persuade the king
to imprison his dear friend Ned?
Robert Baratheon is dead.
Joffrey rules in King's Landing.
My sister rules. you mean.
Stark's son has called his banners.
- He moves south with a strong host.
- A green boy.
One taste of battle and he'll run back
to Winterfell with his tail between his legs.
Maybe. Though the boy does have
a certain belligerence.
You'd like him.
While we're on the subject of war.
I made promises to my friends here.
and a Lannister always pays his debts.
We shall require
3.000 helms and shields.
plus swords. pikes.
gorgets. maces...
If it please my lord.
Ser Addam bids me report
that the northmen
have crossed the Neck.
The wolf rushes
into the lion's jaws. So be it.
Kevan. command
the drummers beat assembly.
And send word to Jaime
that I am moving against Robb Stark.
At once. my lord.
It is said that the men
of the mountain clans are great warriors.
Ride with me against my enemies
and you shall have
all my son promised you and more.
Only if the halfman fights with us.
Until we hold the steel he pledged us.
the little lion's life is ours.
(Rodrik) The scouts report
Lord Tywin moves north.
We need to get him on broken ground.
put his knights at a disadvantage.
No. we need to get around him and break
Jaime Lannister's siege of Riverrun.
Do that and the river lords will join us.
To do either we need to cross the river
and the only crossing is at the Twins.
Lord Frey controls that bridge.
Your father's bannerman.
"The late Lord Frey" my father calls him.
At the Trident. he didn't appear
until the battle was done.
Some men take their oaths
more seriously than others.
(Grunting)
Robb's right.
We need that bridge.
So what's it going to be?
Do we move against
Jaime or Lord Tywin?
Your pardon. my lords.
We've captured a Lannister scout.
Don't worry. lad. He won't be
leaving this tent with his head.
- Where did you find him?
- In the brush above the encampment.
He looked to be counting.
How high did you get?
20.000. Maybe more.
You don't have to do this yourself.
Your father would understand...
My father understands mercy.
when there is room for it.
And he understands honor...
and courage.
Let him go.
Robb.
Tell Lord Tywin
winter is coming for him.
20.000 northerners marching south
to find out if he really does shit gold.
Yes. my lord.
Thank you. my lord.
Are you touched. boy?!
Letting him go?
You call me boy again.
Go on.
(Growls)
Oi.
(Pycelle) It is also the wish of His Grace
that his loyal servant Janos Slynt.
- Commander of the City Watch...
- Ser Aron.
...be at once raised to the rank of lord...
Lord Gyles.
...and granted
the ancient seat of Harrenhal.
and that his sons and grandsons
shall hold this honor
after him until the end of time.
(Lords mutter)
In the place of the traitor Eddard Stark.
it is the wish of His Grace
that Tywin Lannister.
Lord of Casterly Rock
and Warden of the West.
be appointed Hand of the King.
Lastly.
in these times of treason and turmoil.
it is the view of council
that the life and safety
of King Joffrey
be of paramount importance.
Ser Barristan Selmy.
Your Grace.
I am yours to command.
Rise. Ser Barristan.
You may remove your helm.
You have served the realm
long and faithfully.
Every man and woman
in the Seven Kingdoms owes you thanks.
But it is time to put aside
your armor and your sword.
It is time to rest
and look back with pride
- on your many years of service.
- (Murmuring)
Your Grace. the Kingsguard
is a sworn brotherhood.
Our vows are taken for life.
Only death relieves us of our sacred trust.
Whose death. Ser Barristan?
Yours or your king's?
(Joffrey) You let my father die.
You're too old to protect anybody.
- Your Grace...
- The council has determined
that Ser Jaime Lannister
will take your place
- as Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
- The man who profaned his blade
with the blood of the king
he had sworn to defend!
Careful. ser.
We have nothing but gratitude
for your long service. good ser.
You shall be given
a stout keep beside the sea.
with servants
to look after your every need.
A hall to die in
and men to bury me.
I am a knight.
I shall die a knight.
A naked knight. apparently.
(Laughter)
Even now I could cut through
the five of you like carving a cake!
Here. boy!
Melt it down and add it to the others.
(Doors creak. clang)
If any man in this hall
has other matters
to set before His Grace.
let him speak now
or go forth and hold his silence.
Your Grace.
Come forward. my lady.
(Steward) The Lady Sansa
of House Stark.
Do you have some business
for the king and the council. Sansa?
I do.
As it please Your Grace.
I ask mercy for my father.
Lord Eddard Stark.
who was Hand of the King.
Treason is a noxious weed.
- It should be torn out. root...
- Let her speak.
I want to hear what she says.
Thank you. Your Grace.
Do you deny your father's crime?
No. my lords.
I know he must be punished.
All I ask is mercy.
I know my lord father
must regret what he did.
He was King Robert's friend
and he loved him.
You all know he loved him.
He never wanted to be Hand
until the king asked him.
They must have lied to him -
Lord Renly or Lord Stannis or somebody.
They must have lied!
He said I wasn't the king.
- Why did he say that?
- He was badly hurt.
Maester Pycelle
was giving him milk of the poppy.
He wasn't himself.
Otherwise he never would have said it.
A child's faith.
Such sweet innocence.
And yet they say wisdom
oft comes from the mouths of babes.
Treason is treason!
Anything else?
If you still have any affection
in your heart for me.
please do me this kindness. Your Grace.
Your sweet words have moved me.
But your father has to confess.
He has to confess
and say that I'm the king...
or there'll be no mercy for him.
He will.